proto.io 2019-05-11

# Privacy Policy - Proto.io

**Last Updated: May 15, 2018**

This Privacy Policy explains how information about you is collected, used and disclosed by PROTOIO Inc. and its affiliates (collectively, " **Proto.io** ", " **we** " or " **us** "). This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect when you use our website, and other products and services (collectively, the " **Services** ") or when you otherwise interact with us. 

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our homepage or sending you an email notification). We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services to stay informed about our information practices and the choices available to you.

### COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

#### Information You Provide to Us

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you create an account, request customer support or otherwise communicate with us. The types of information we may collect include basic user information (such as your name, email address and photograph), company information, financial information (such as your payment card number, expiration date and security code) and any other information you choose to provide. 

#### Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Services 

When you access or use our Services, we automatically collect information about you, including:

  * **Log Information:** We log information about your use of the Services, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address and the page you visited before navigating to our Services.
  * **Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:** We use various technologies to collect information, and this may include sending cookies to your computer or mobile device. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us to improve our Services and your experience, see which areas and features of our Services are popular and count visits. We may also collect information using web beacons (also known as "tracking pixels"). Web beacons are electronic images that may be used in our Services or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and determine whether an email has been opened and acted upon. For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see "Your Choices" below.

### USE OF INFORMATION

We use information about you to provide, maintain, and improve our Services, such as to process transactions and send you related information, including confirmations and invoices. We may also use the information we collect to do the following:

  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, rewards, and events offered by Proto.io and others, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with our Services; 
  * Personalize and improve the Services and provide content or features that match user profiles or interests;
  * Process and deliver contest entries and rewards; and
  * Carry out any other purpose described to you at the time the information was collected.

### SHARING OF INFORMATION

We may share information about you as follows or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * With vendors, consultants and other service providers who need access to such information to carry out work on our behalf;
  * In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with any applicable law, regulation or legal process, or as otherwise required by any applicable law, rule or regulation;
  * If we believe your actions are inconsistent with the spirit or language of our user agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property and safety of Proto.io or others;
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business to another company; and
  * With your consent or at your direction.

We may also share aggregated or de-identified information, which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.

### SOCIAL SHARING FEATURES

The Services may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools, which let you share actions you take on our Services with other media, and vice versa. The use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.

### ADVERTISING AND ANALYTICS SERVICES PROVIDED BY OTHERS

We may allow others to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet and to provide analytics services. These entities may use cookies, web beacons and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and conversion information. This information may be used by Proto.io and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, delivery advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites and better understand your online activity. For more information about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes, please visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices) and [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). Customers in the EU may visit [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/).

### SECURITY

Proto.io takes reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

### DATA RETENTION

We store the information we collect for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it. We may retain certain information for legitimate business purposes or as required by law.

### INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS

Proto.io is based in the United States and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law. By accessing or using the Services or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing, storage and transfer of information in and to the United States and other countries where you may not have the same rights and protections as you do under local law.

### YOUR CHOICES

#### Account Information

You may update, correct or delete information about you at any time by logging into your account and editing your user profile or billing details. If you wish to delete your account, please cancel your account in the billing section for your account or email us at [info@proto.io](mailto:info@proto.io) or [support@proto.io](mailto:support@proto.io), but note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period of time. 

#### Cookies

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Services.

You can consult our Cookie Statement for more details on the services that use cookies.

#### Promotional Communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from Proto.io by following the instructions in those communications. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

### RESIDENTS OF THE EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain additional rights and protections under the law regarding the processing of your personal data.

#### Legal Basis for Processing

If you are a resident of the EEA, we will only process your personal data:

  * To perform our responsibilities under our contract with you (e.g. processing payments for and providing the Services you have requested);
  * When we have a legitimate interest in processing your personal data (e.g. to communicate with you about changes to our Services, to advertise our Services, and to provide, secure, and improve our Services); or
  * To comply with our legal or regulatory obligations.

#### Data Subject Requests

If you are a resident of the EEA, you have the right to access personal data we hold about you and to have certain personal data corrected or erased. You may also have the right to restrict certain processing of your data.

To make any of these requests please email [dpo@proto.io](mailto:dpo@proto.io). We will respond as soon as practicable and no later than one month after receipt of your request. We may request proof of identification to verify your request.

We may deny or restrict fulfillment of your request in some cases, such as when your access to data places another individual's privacy rights at risk, or the continued processing of your data is necessary to comply with a legal obligation. If so, we will notify you of the reason(s) for this denial.

#### Questions or Complaints

If you are a resident of the EEA and have a concern about our processing of personal data that we are not able to resolve, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the data privacy authority where you reside. For contact details of your local Data Protection Authority, please see <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>.

### CONTACT US

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [legal@proto.io](mailto:legal@proto.io).
